{
  "fileName": "Quiz Miller_Spoolman Living in the Environment 16e, Chapter, Chapter 13.pdf.txt",
  "questions": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "The world\u0027s single biggest cause of illness is",
      "choices": [
        "a lack of adequate shelter.",
        "a lack of clean water for drinking and sanitation.",
        "a lack of healthy food to eat.",
        "airborne viruses and bacteria."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "We interfere with the Hydrologic Cycle if we",
      "choices": [
        "pollute our water.",
        "withdraw too much ground water.",
        "all of the choices",
        "destroy wetlands and remove large forests."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Fortunately, the resource freshwater is fairly evenly divided throughout nations and continents.",
      "choices": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Groundwater refers to",
      "choices": [
        "freshwater above the ground.",
        "all liquid freshwater.",
        "all liquid and frozen freshwater.",
        "freshwater beneath the ground."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Annual surface runoff in rivers and streams not lost by seasonal floods, and therefore available for human use, is called",
      "choices": [
        "watershed.",
        "reliable surface runoff.",
        "surface water.",
        "groundwater."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "One in ________ people per year lack regular access to enough clean water for drinking, cooking, and washing.",
      "choices": [
        "50",
        "33",
        "6",
        "14"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "The current land area experiencing severe or extreme drought is approximately",
      "choices": [
        "30%",
        "3%",
        "50%",
        "10%"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Water is limited, resulting in competition for this resource. In the U.S., competition for water results in",
      "choices": [
        "equal distribution of water.",
        "industry getting a disproportionately smaller share.",
        "farmers getting a disproportionately smaller share.",
        "cities getting a disproportionately smaller share."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Cities provide water to their citizens. The majority of these citizens",
      "choices": [
        "pay a water bill to government-owned water companies.",
        "get their water for free.",
        "do not get billed for water use; taxes pay their water costs.",
        "pay a water bill to privately owned water companies."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Aquifers",
      "choices": [
        "are usually naturally renewable by rainwater.",
        "all of the choices",
        "should continue to provide more than enough water for drinking and irrigation well into the future.",
        "are relatively rare."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Land subsidence and sinkholes are problems that sometimes occur as water is withdrawn. These sometimes occur in/at/beneath",
      "choices": [
        "the Rocky Mountains, where water is withdrawn from rivers.",
        "the Great Lakes, as we pump clean water from beneath the lakes.",
        "middle and southwestern states where the aquifer beneath is being depleted.",
        "all of the choices"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Hydroelectric dams along large rivers",
      "choices": [
        "allow production of relatively cheap electricity.",
        "disrupt fish migration and spawning.",
        "reduce soil fertility downriver by preventing flooding",
        "all of the choices"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "For desert cities such as Las Vegas, Nevada, aquifers and ground water have been depleted. The city recycles its water used in bathing, swimming pools, and fountains. Given the need for drinking water in such a large city, the source of the water must be",
      "choices": [
        "water piped from other communities.",
        "rainwater.",
        "surface lakes and reservoirs.",
        "recycled water."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "There are no disadvantages of hydroelectric dams.",
      "choices": [
        "False",
        "True"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Both California and China have plans to move vast amounts of water from one part of the land to another. The primary reason that each feels water need to be moved is",
      "choices": [
        "the people in water-poor areas have squandered their water, and need more to survive.",
        "water is absolutely needed for the industries in these water-poor areas.",
        "the water-rich areas can afford to give water to highly populated, water-poor areas.",
        "this will stimulate these economies by employing many people to build the pipes/aqueducts/etc. to move the water."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Forcing saltwater through a membrane filter with extremely small pores to produce freshwater is called",
      "choices": [
        "distillation.",
        "reverse osmosis.",
        "infiltration.",
        "irrigation."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "According to water experts, the main cause of water waste is",
      "choices": [
        "washing cars.",
        "water leaks in pipes.",
        "evaporation.",
        "water doesn\u0027t cost enough."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "The single biggest domestic water use in the U.S. is",
      "choices": [
        "flushing toilets.",
        "washing cars.",
        "automatic dishwashers.",
        "baths and showers."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "A natural area that is prone to flooding is called a",
      "choices": [
        "dam.",
        "floodplain.",
        "levy.",
        "watershed."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    }
  ]
}